Nestor D. Pereira Neto

FLECTRONIC ENGINEER : 36

Street Eduardo Campos nº 10, Boca do Rio, Salvador - BA, Brazil, 41705-230

■ (71) 9 9698-6755 | ■ nestor-dp@hotmail.com | ● lattes.cnpq.br/8490310764316084 | ■ nestorpneto | • NestorDP

"I have a degree in Electronic Engineering (2013) and a specialization in Biomedical Engineering (2019). I have experience in the maintenance of diagnostic imaging hospital equipment. In 2011, I started to work as a teacher in technical and higher education courses. I am currently finishing my Masters in Electrical Engineering at the Federal University of Bahia in the area of computing and robotics. Since 2019 I have had the pleasure of working in research and development in the field of robotics. Main areas of interest: C/C++ Programming; Embedded systems; Real-time systems and Mobile robotics localization and navigation."

Education

Federal University of Bahia - UFBA

Salvador, BA

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING - RESEARCH LINE: COMPUTING AND ROBOTICS

Apr. 2018 - Mar. 2022

- · Communication between Robot Operating System ROS and System-on-a-chip SoC with integrated FPGA.
- Scholarship from Higher Education Personal Improvement Coordination CAPES

Estácio de Sá University

Salvador, BA

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2019

SPECIALIZATION IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING

• Convolutional Neural Network for Detection of QRS Complexes in Electrocardiogram Signals

Faculty of Science and Technology - ÁREA1

Salvador, BA

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

Feb. 2008 - Jul. 2013

- · Command prototype to fit X-ray equipment to the standards required by the National Health Surveillance Agency ANVISA.
- Undergraduate research scholarship for two years

Experiências Profissionais

SENAI - CIMATEC Salvador, BA

CONSULTANT II - ROBOTIC ENGINEERING

Apr. 2022 - currently

- ROS2 robotics framework: Gazebo Simulation, URDF/Xacro, SLAM Techniques for UGV.
- Programming C/C++ and python.
- · Hardware and software integration.
- Hardware and firmware development for embedded systems.

CONSULTANT II - ROBOTIC ENGINEERING

Apr. 2019 - Apr. 2022

- ROS robotics framework: Gazebo Simulation, URDF/Xacro.
- Programming C/C++ and python.
- · Hardware and software integration.
- Hardware and firmware development for embedded systems.

Professor part time - 20H

Nov. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Teach class for the course: Industrial Mechatronics.
- Subjects: Analog Electronics and Digital Eletronic.

ÁREA1|Wyden College Salvador, BA

LABORATORY TECHNICIAN

Jul. 2013 - Aug. 2017

- · Prepare and teach practical classes for the courses: Computer Engineering, Electrical Engineering and Automation Engineering.
- · Test new tools used in laboratories and provide training.
- Provide extension courses and the experience program.

Alfamed Eletromedicina Engineer - Technical responsible

Salvador, BA

• Technical responsible for the company.

Aug. 2013 - Feb. 2015

Electronic maintenance in hospital bio-imaging equipment.

Centro Territorial de Educação Profissional da Região Metropolitana CETEP-RM

Camaçari, BA

TEACHER - 40H

jun. 2011 - jun. 2013

- · Teach classes in the following subjects: Analog and digital electronics; Microcontrollers; Electric circuits.
- Guide students in their course completion work.

Jun. 2009 - Sep. 2010

MAINTENANCE TECHNICIAN

· Preventive and corrective maintenance in hospital bioimaging equipment.

Mar. 2008 - Jun. 2009 INTERN - MAINTENANCE

• Preventive and corrective maintenance in hospital bioimaging equipment.

Idiomas

Português Nativo.

Inglês Nível intermediário.

Cursos

Treinamento em Tecnologia FPGA INTEL (20h), Macnica DHW - Centro Oficial de Treinamento FPGA INTEL 2021 Florianópolis, SC

2018 NucLi - Inglês. Compreensão horal (32h), Universidade Federal da Bahia - UFBA Salvador, BA

2010 Estudo do Controle de Dispositivos via portas paralela, serial e USB (60h), Faculdade ÁREA1. Salvador, BA

Eletrônica Analógica Aplicada (30h), Faculdade ÁREA1. 2010

Projects and Research

SENAI CIMATEC Salvador, BA

SuBot - CTG Brasil (China Three Gorges Corporation)

Out. 2021 - Atualmente

- Mobile robotics development project for inspection of high voltage substations. • Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ and Python language.
- Hardware and firmware development for actuator systems and peripheral communication.
- Electronic project development.

DIGISUB - PETROBRAS Abrp. 2019 - Oct. 2021

- 3D digitizer development project of underwater surfaces in deep water.
- Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ and Python language.
- Hardware and firmware development for actuator systems and peripheral communication.
- Prototype power system sizing: sources, AC-DC/DC-DC converters, batteries.

Escola Politécnica da Universidade Federal da Bahia - UFBA

Salvador, BA

Salvador, BA

PROJETO DE MESTRADO Dez. 2018 - atualmente

- 1 GigE communication development between FPGA and ROS.
- Hardware project in verilog for implementation in SOC/FPGA (Cyclone V Intel).
- Socket programming in C/C++ language for linux.
- Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ language.

Faculdade ÁREA1 Salvador, BA Jul. 2011 - Jul. 2013

INICIAÇÃO CIENTÍFICA

- Development of a microcontrolled command to fit old X-ray equipment to current technical standards.
- Programming 8051 family microcontrollers in assembly language.
- Research of the technical standards established by ANVISA in relation to X-ray equipment.
- Presentation of monthly reports with activities developed in the period.
- Publication of the results in an article in the journal Cientefico ISSN 1677-1591, jul/dez 2013.

Competências e Habilidades

Verilog HDL, Sockets, Cmake, GDB, Nios II, FreeRTOS, Embedded Linux, SimuLink.

Intermediário Python, ARM Cortex M, Linux, Git/Github, PIC, AutoCAD, ROS/Gazebo.

Avançado Layout de circuito impresso/KiCad, Matlab, C/C++, AVR, 8051, GNU-Make, LaTeX.

Presentation

27th IBERCHIP (Reverse Engineering Conference)

Santiago, Chile

1-4 Mar. 2022

• Comunicação entre Robot Operating System - ROS e SoC com FPGA integrado